

Josep Batallé

Researcher and Fullstack developer



jbatalle3@gmail.com



https://goo.gl/pK9ss1



https://github.com/jbatalle



ABOUT

MSc. Josep Batallé is a research engineer at i2CAT Foundation since 2013. He obtained his Technical Engineer in Telecommunications at Rovira i Virgili University (2011) and his Master in Telematics engineering at the Technical University of Catalonia (2013). He has been involved in several European projects such as T-NOVA, GEYSERS, DOLFIN, CHARISMA, SESAME and OFERTIE involving the most relevant topics of the last five years: Network Function Virtualization (NFV), Software Defined Networks (SDN), Network as a Service (NaaS), 5G and so on. Currently he is working in T-NOVA, taking care of the design and development of the core of TeNOR. TeNOR is a NFV orchestrator totally integrated with Openstack and Opendaylight (ODL) that follows the NFV ETSI standards.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Research and projects engineer, i2CAT Foundation

Nov 2013 - Present ② 3 years

- Designer and main developer of the NFV orchestrator for the T-NOVA project: TeNOR (https://github.com/T-NOVA/TeNOR)
- Designer and developer of an OpenAccess platform for the CONTENT, SODALES and CHARISMA projects.
- Developer of multiple User interfaces (Dashboard) for several projects
- Coworking with CISCO and Barcelona City Council in a proof of concept about FOG Computing
- Technologies used: Ruby, Java, Javascript, MongoDB, ElasticSearch.

Intership, i2CAT Foundation

Dec 2012 - Oct 2013 ② 10 months

i2CAT Foundation is a non-profit research and innovation centre which promotes mission-oriented R+D+i activities on advanced Internet architectures, applications and services. The centre stands up for a new open innovation framework, fostering the collaboration between companies, public administration, the academic environment and end-users.

- Designer and developer of a Management interface for GEYSERS project. Implementation of the backend in a Network as a Service
- Proof of concept in NFV.
- Technologies used: Java, Javascript, HTML.

Intership, Artic-Group

Jun 2012 - Nov 2012 ② 5 months

Artic Group was a technology consulting and specialized in web presence and positioning.

- Development of several webs for different clients. Most importan client: solomoto.es
- Technologies used: PHP, Bash, HTML.



EDUCATION

MSc Telematics Engineering, Master, Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona)

Jun 2013 - Jan 2011

BSc Telematics Engineering, Bachelor, Universitat Rovira i Virgili (Tarragona)

Jun 2008 - Jan 2011



SKILLS

Backend: Ruby (Sinatra, Rails), Java (OSGI, Karaf, Spring, Hibernate), Python (Django), NodeJS, RabbitMq.

Frontend: HTML && CSS, Javascript(AngularJS, D3js, Visjs), PHP (Drupal, Wordpress).

Databases: SQL: MySQL, Postgre, NoSQL: MongoDB, EApache Cassandra, ElasticSearch.

DevOps: Ansible, Vagrant, Docker, OpenStack.

Networking: SDN (Openflow, ODL, vSwitch), NFV, IPv6.

Source control and CI/CD: Jenkins, Travis, Git, SVN.



PROJECTS

TeNOR, http://github.com/T-NOVA/TeNOR

Published on: 2014-08-24

NFV Orchestrator platform developed by the T-NOVA project, responsible for managing the entire NFV lifecycle service.



Awards

Student ICT research project competition, Techcrunch

Awarded on: Nov 2013

Best student project



Publications

TeNOR: Steps towards an orchestration platform for multi-PoP NFV deployment, IEEE

Published on: Jun 06, 2016

$\label{lem:concept} \mbox{ Virtual network function scheduling: Concept and challenges , \ \mbox{ IEEE } \\$

Published on: Jun 18, 2014

On the Implementation of NFV over an OpenFlow Infrastructure: Routing Function Virtualization , IEEE

Published on: Nov 11, 2013

${\bf Management\ of\ Virtual\ Infrastructures\ through\ OpenNaaS\ ,\ IEEE}$

Published on: Jun 17, 2013



Languages

English (Fluent), Spanish (Native speaker), Catalan (Native speaker).